Mark Sirany

11191 Aberdeen Street NE Unit H, Blaine, MN 55449 | Cell: (612) 867-2808 | <u>Isirany@icloud.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/Isirany/</u> | Portfolio: <u>Isirany.github.io/profile3/</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/Isirany/</u>

Professional Summary

I am a Full Stack Web developer with ten years of experience in technical writing. I have formal education and career experience as a Full Stack Web Developer and in UX Design with Valmont Industries, Plumbline Builders of Minnesota, and Blatchford Engine Repair.

I have worked with engineers, service technicians, product managers, and marketing teams to create and implement websites and web applications. These experiences motivated me to continue my career journey in creating applications that help businesses and customers.

I designed, managed, and updated Valmont's Irrigation Division international product documentation website and managed the content database for the domestic product documentation website. This required continuous translation management and updating into 16 languages. I also created the Plumbline Builders of Minnesota's company website and a web application for Blatchford Engine Repair.

Technical Summary

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Web APIs, AJAX, Node Servers, Express.js, MySQL, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, React, WordPress, Node.js, Bootstrap, Android, Git, PHP, ASP
- 3D CAD Design Software (SolidWorks, SolidWorks Composer)
- Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, Reader)
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Visio, Access, OneNote)
- Google (Analytics, AdSense, AdWords)

Professional Experience

FavColorRust.com Web Designer/Web Developer

May 2015 - Present

Created Favorite Color Rust Digital Magazine to showcase my editing, publishing, writing, and management of online multimedia content.

- Webmaster, writer, and social media manager
- Created dynamic, interactive content with the focus on information, technology, and entertainment
- Content strategy, develop brand awareness, generate inbound traffic and cultivate leads and sales

Engineered Component Solutions - Minneapolis, MN Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

February 2020

• Created a custom website. Both front end and back end coding using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Express.

Blatchford Engine Repair - Minneapolis, MN Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

February 2020

 Created a custom web application for tracking vehicle repairs. Both front end and back end coding using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Express.

Plumbline Builders of Minneapolis - Minneapolis, MN Web Designer/Developer

February 2017 - February 2019

• Designed, created, and deployed company website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Xigent Solutions - Plymouth, MN Technical Writer

September 2018 - September 2019

- Developed internal content plan including workflow and processes that facilitated the creation of consistent and accurate statement of work for client engagements.
- Developed and maintained a library of technical content through the creation and implementation of company document repository.
- Worked with the Sales Team to plan, develop, organize, write and edit SOWs for customer projects.

Avionte Software Digital Content Writer

April 2018 - June 2018

- Write engaging content for inbound leting campaigns
- Write and optimize compelling long-form and short-form copy and content for multiple channels including, but not limited to, collateral, website, blogs, ads, social, case studies, email, press releases and a variety of value-add content pieces
- Manage researching, writing, editing, and proofing of digital and print materials on deadline
- Ensure all content is SEO optimized
- Work with digital leting to optimize content based on analytics and make recommendations to improve performance
- Help develop, communicate, and execute content plans and social campaigns
- Update and maintain all content across the sales team

Conductix-Wamplfer

May 2017 - March 2018

Journalist and Engineering Technical Writer

Shared service position working for both the leting department and the engineering department. Work assignments included:

- Job Application Stories and Job Reference Summaries, Web Site Copy, Press Releases, Newsletter articles, Advertising copy for technical publications, Catalog and brochure copy, Video Scripts, and Instruction, Operations, and Maintenance Manuals
- Personally responsible for creating and implementing a new documentation review process for the engineering department.
- Personally responsible for creating and implementing a new standard design for all engineering documentation.

Hive Media Group Contract Digital Content Writer

July 2016 - February 2017

Writer of articles for online publication

Valmont Industries Inc - Valley, NE

October 2012 - October 2015

Project Manager Technical Writer / Illustrator / Web Content Manager

for Irrigation Division products

- Designed, managed, and updated Valmont Irrigation Division's international product documentation website.
- Managed the content database for Valmont Irrigation Division's domestic product documentation website
- Created and managed the project for international translation of product manuals into 16 languages, coordinating product/engineering change management of over 400 documents
- Department specialist for electronic control panels, user interface testing and member of mechanical, electronic, software engineering product team
- Over 103 projects successfully completed and implemented during employment
- Coordination specialist for field service documentation used for product installation and training

Notable Projects

- Vehicle Repair Tracker
 - Web application for tracking vehicle repairs.
 - Both front end and back end coding using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Express.
 - Deployed link: https://siranyrepair.herokuapp.com/

- GitHub link: https://github.com/marksirany/vehicle-repair-tracker
- Community Blog Website
 - Full stack project to create a blog/news site where web development boot camp students voice opinions and advice.
 - Both front end and back end coding using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase, Node.js, mySQL, MAMP, JawsDB, Express, and ESLint.
 - Deployed link: https://keep-it-code.herokuapp.com/
 - GitHub link: https://github.com/marksirany/codingcommunityblog
- Weather Dashboard
 - Web app that utilizes the openweathermap API to show the current weather and the 5 day forecast of any city that the user searches.
 - Deployed link: https://marksirany.github.io/weatherjs/
 - GitHub link: https://github.com/marksirany/weatherjs

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Minnesota-Twin Cities	2019 – 2020
Certificate in User Experience University of Michigan	2017 - 2018
Bachelor's Degree in English	
Specialization in American Literature and Creative Writing	2010 2010
University of Nebraska at Omaha - Omaha, NE	2013 - 2016